VENKATA BOMMIREDDIPALLI



0423492020 | <u>venkatab144@gmail.com</u>



https://vbi.dev/

https://github.com/venkatab144



https://www.linkedin.com/in/venkata-bommireddipalli-9a31a9aa/

SUMMARY

Passionate and dedicated individual having five years of professional industry experience developing Enterprise Level Applications. Well-versed in development and testing for a leading logistics company. Extremely fast and eager learner seeking roles designing and developing full-stack web, backend, mobile or machine learning projects.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

November 2016 - Present

WiseTech Global

- Developed deep and extensive knowledge of C# and SQL, as well as strong Systems Architecture and Design principles.
- Implemented and followed a strict Test-driven Development (TDD) approach to ensure code was of highest quality and bug free.
- Designed, developed and thoroughly tested various projects for WiseTech's; CRM, Customs and CORE Architecture software.
- · Responsible for development and maintenance of complex Commission Management system.
- Used full React, Node.js, C# .NET and SQL stack to design and implement features for WiseTech's internal developer website.
- · Worked efficiently in an AGILE environment ensuring timely completion of projects.
- Mentored and assisted interns working in my team.
- Conducted code reviews and functional reviews to ensure all code was production ready.
- · Communicated effectively with clients to gather project requirements and information regarding defects/bugs encountered.

Instore Staff

October 2016 - November 2016

Domino's

- Assisted in managing staff schedule.
- Assisted in managing day-to-day in-store activities such as delivery and station rotations.

Software Engineer - Intern

December 2014

WiseTech Global

- Developed small-scale features for WiseTech's Distributed Auto Tester (DAT).
- Participated in pair reviews with Senior Engineer to gain valuable development experience.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering with Honours (Software Engineering)

March 2017 - November 2021 (Expected)

University of Technology Sydney

- Currently hold a Distinction 75+ WAM (Weighted Average Mark).
- Achieved a High Distinction 90+ WAM in Data Analytics Sub-major.

Diploma in Professional Engineering Practice

March 2017 - November 2021 (Expected)

University of Technology Sydney

National Computer Science School (NCSS)

January 2016

University of Sydney, School of Computer Science

- Received a scholarship to attend NCSS.
- Wrote and deployed complex C code on the Arduino for an embedded robotic system that enabled automatic path following using infrared sensors.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

C#

SQL

C/C++

JavaScript

.NET

HTML/CSS

Java

Python

ReactJS

Node.js

Visual Studio/Visual Studio Code

MSSMS

Android Studio

Microsoft Office

Git

TFS

Azure

NUnit